在这篇文章中，我们将看到一个强大的想法，叫做
In this reading, we're going to look at a powerful idea called
抽象数据类型，使我们能够分离
abstract data types, which enable us to separate how
我们在程序中使用数据结构
we use a data structure in a program
从数据结构本身的特定形式。
from the particular form of the data structure itself.
抽象数据类型解决了一个特别危险的问题，
Abstract data types address a particularly dangerous problem,
客户对该类型的
clients making assumptions about the type's
内部代表。
internal representation.
我们会知道为什么这是危险的，以及你如何避免它。
We'll see why this is dangerous and how you can avoid it.
我们还将讨论操作的分类
We'll also discuss the classification of operations
以及对抽象数据类型进行良好设计的一些原则。
and some principles of good design for abstract data types.
我们开始吧。
Let's get started.